Guide to the William T. Grant Foundation records FA004
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Special Formats, 1931-1995; 5; Grant, W. T. (William Thomas) (1876-1972); W.T. Grant (Firm); Harvard Study of Adult Development; William T. Grant Foundation. Commission on Work, Family, and Citizenship; 2.57 Cubic Feet 27 reels, 3 photo boxes, 2 oversize boxes, 3 letter document boxes, and 1 half-
  - Audiovisual and digital material, 1960-1989; C; 27 reels and 2 boxes
    - The Angels of Serra Center - Arthur Zegart, probably 1970s; 2006.113.22; 1 reel and 1 folder of supplemental material; 16mm film (Reel AV 3062, Box 286a, Folder 3624)
      Produced, directed and written by Arthur Zegart, Serra Residential Center, Freemont, California
      Produced in association with the National Council of Churches
      Documentary footage at the Serra Residential Center. Focuses on adults with mental disabilities and mental retardation, and the center's efforts to support the integration of these adults into the Freemont, California community.
    - Loving Parents - University of Pennsylvania, Hospital of the University of Pennsylvania - Luigi Mastroianni, Jr., 1978; 2006.113.23; 1 reel; 16mm film (Reel AV 3063)
      Written and directed by Herman J. Engel
      Produced for the Hospital of the University of Pennsylvania.
      Consultants: Luigi Mastroianni, M.D.; Emily Mudd, Ph.D.; Helen Dickens, M.D.
      Funded by the Grant Foundation; the Van Ameringen Foundation
      Documentary footage of an educational session for parents that helps them become better teachers in their children's sex education.
    - Fulfillment of Human Potential - Doris E. Hadary, probably 1970s; 2006.113.24; 16mm film (Reel AV 3064)
      Laboratory Science and Art for Blind, Deaf, and Disturbed Children in a Mainstream Setting
      Dr. Doris E. Hadary, Program Director, Laboratory Science and Art for the Blind and Deaf
      Funded by the Grant Foundation; the Redskin Foundation
      Produced through the American University
      Documentary footage of hearing impaired children, visually impaired children, and children with other disabilities in the learning environment. Focus is on the child's observations, critical thinking, description, and creation throughout the learning process.
    - Downey Side: The Other Face of Juvenile Justice - Arthur Zegart, probably 1970s; 2006.113.25; 16mm film (Reel AV 3065)
      Documentary footage at the Downey Home, a permanent home for at-risk adolescents. Adults live and work in the home alongside these adolescents in a parental role for a duration of three years.
    - Lab Science and Art Program for the Visually Impaired - Doris E. Hadary, Ph.D., undated; 2006.113.26; 16mm film (Reel AV 3066)
      Laboratory Science Enrichment Program, Part II
    - First Friends - The Mental Health Film Board - Alberta Jacoby, probably 1970s; 2006.113.27; 16mm film (Box 286a, Folder 3625, Reel AV 3067)
      The Mental Health Film Board and the Yale Child Study Center present
      "Years of Growth: Studies in Development"
      "First Friends"
      Written and directed by Irving Jacoby
      Consultant: Alberta Jacoby, M.P.H.
      Head Start Program, Danbury CT
      Made possible by the Grant Foundation
      "First Friends shows how a child becomes part of a group. Set in a pre-school, youngsters play together and reveal a wide range of feelings, attitudes, and behavior." - The Mental Health Film Board, Inc.
    - Dental Detective - Health Futures, Children's Health Futures - Stephen R. Mosow (84-0999-84), 1986; 5.25 inch floppy disc (Box 287, Folder 3633)
    - Don't Break the Camel's Back - Health Futures, Children's Health Futures - Stephen R. Mosow (84-0999-84), 1986; 5.25 inch floppy disc (Box 287, Folder 3634)
    - Nutrients, Calories - Health Futures, Children's Health Futures - Stephen R. Mosow (84-0999-84), 1986; 5.25 inch floppy disc (Box 287, Folder 3635)
    - Your Children, Our Children - Twin Cities Public Television - John Merrow, 1984; Audiocassettes; 2 audiocassette tapes (Box 287, Folder 3636)
- Accession 2016:081, 1998-2012; 6
  - Board of Trustees Meetings - Minutes, 1998-2006 (Box 288, Folder 1-4)
  - Presidential Search - Questions Raised, 1998 (Box 288, Folder 5)
  - Robert Granger Correspondence - William T. Grant Store, 2006; 2012 (Box 288, Folder 6)
  - Robert Granger Correspondence - William Brooks, Calvin Coolidge Memorial Foundation, 2009 (Box 288, Folder 7)
  - Robert Granger Correspondence - Matthew A. Gelbin, "The Grant Game" Publication, 2005; 2009 (Box 288, Folder 8)